Preliminary Inventory of the James Hastings Wolfe papers
Hoover Institution Archives
James Hastings Wolfe papers
1964-2007
2016C2
Hoover Institution Archives
12 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (5.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, notes, memoranda, reports, studies, statements, proposals, resolutions, and printed matter relating to the disputed status of Cyprus and especially to the application of international law to the matter.
Wolfe, James Hastings.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2015.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical note
American political scientist.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, writings, notes, memoranda, reports, studies, statements, proposals, resolutions, and printed matter relating to the disputed status of Cyprus and especially to the application of international law to the matter.
Cyprus--History--Cyprus Crisis, 1974-
- Comments prepared by Rauf R. Denktas on a paper written by James Wolfe, 1979 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Greek Cypriot statements, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Clippings, printed matter and memoranda regarding Cyprus, 1983 October - 1984 January (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Greek and Turkish Cypriot settlers, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Events and chronology of Cyprus, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Constitutional proposals, 1984-1999 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Correspondence from Rauf R. Denktas, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Materials regarding, and correspondence with, Rauf R. Denktas, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Correspondence with Zaim Necatigil, chairman of the Turkish Cypriot Human Rights Committee, 1979-1990 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus elections, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- "Cyprus: Ethnic Conflict and Tensions," by Vamik D. Volkan, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Articles, memoranda, and clippings regarding Turkish Cypriots, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 12)
- Correspondence with M. Necati Münir Ertekün, 1979-1990 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
- Report from the United Nations Secretary General on the United Nations Operation in Cyprus, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Correspondence with Rauf R. Denktas, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Copies of United Nations Security Council records, 1965 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Materials regarding the United Nations resolutions, 1983 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Javier Perez de Cuella, 1983 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- United Nations reports, clippings, and press releases, 1985 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- "Seminar on Cyprus: The Question of a Transitional Government," by James H. Wolfe, 1992 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- K. Waldheim evaluation paper, 1981 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- United Nations Security Council materials, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 2: 11-14)
  Includes clippings, notes, resolutions, transcripts of meetings, and reports.
- United Nations proposal, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- United Nations forces, 1967-1992 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- Department of State, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Turkish Cypriot documents, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- "The United Nations, International Conflict, and American Security," by George L. Sherry and "Rethinking Cyprus," by Dr. Hugo J. Gobbi, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- United States Department of State press release, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Correspondence and clippings from and regarding Rauf R. Denktas, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 3: 7-9)
- Norwegian Institute of International Affairs, Cyprus workshop, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 10)
- "The Cyprus Conflict and the Role of the United Nations," and "Peacekeeping and Peacemaking: the Role of the United Nations in the Cyprus Conflict," by Kiell Skielsbaek, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 3: 11)
- Correspondence with Ambassador Nelson C. Ledsky, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- United States Department of State Cyprus seminar, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 2)
- Nimetz, Matthew, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 3)
- Boehm, Richard W., 1984-1992 (Box-folder 4: 4)
- Ewing, Raymond C., 1978-1983 (Box-folder 4: 5)
- Papioannou, Ezekias, 1983 (Box-folder 4: 6)
- Iacovou, George, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 7)
- Chrysostomides, Kypros, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- Baroness Elles, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4: 9)
- Tornaritis, Criton G., 1983-1985 (Box-folder 4: 10)
- Notes regarding Cyprus from 1878-1960, 1988 (Box-folder 4: 11)
- Press releases, United Nations resolutions, and clippings, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 12)
- New approaches to negotiation, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 13)
- Greek Cypriot statements, 1986 (Box-folder 4: 14)
- International law, 1983 (Box-folder 4: 15)
- Nejatigil, Zaim M., 2002 (Box-folder 4: 16)
- Takey Crist, et al. v. Republic of Turkey, 1997 (Box-folder 4: 17)
- Burnham, Inc. Publishers, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 4: 18)
- Clerides, Glafcos, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 4: 19)
- Papadopoulos, Tassos, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 4: 20)
- Clippings from Rauf R. Denktas, 2002 (Box-folder 4: 21)
- United Nations Security Council Plan, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 4: 22)
- Autocephalous Greek-Orthodox Church of Cyprus and Republic of Cyprus v. Goldberg and Feldman Fine Arts, Inc. and Peg Goldberg, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 5: 1)
- "Cyprus: My Deposition," by Glafkos Clerides, 1989 (Box-folder 5: 2)
- Legal status of the Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus, 1990 (Box-folder 5: 3)
- Copy of "Euro Court Condemns Turkey for Cyprus Rights Abuse," New York Times, 2001 (Box-folder 5: 4)
- Leigh, Monroe, 1990 (Box-folder 5: 5)
- Hesperides Hotels Limited and Others v. Muftizade, 1984 (Box-folder 5: 6)
- Emergency powers of Justice Triantafyllides, 1964 (Box-folder 5: 7)
- "Do You Remember the Iphestos Files?," by Korkmaz Haktanir, 2001 (Box-folder 5: 8)
- Treaty texts of the Zurich and London Accords, 1990 (Box-folder 5: 9)
- Telex to Cyprus Embassies, 1983 (Box-folder 5: 10)
- "Towards a New Cyprus Republic," by Zaim M. Nejatigil, undated (Box-folder 5: 11)
- "Guidelines Agreed in Nicosia Between President Makarios and Mr. Denktas on February 12th, 1977,", undated (Box-folder 5: 12)
- Recommendation 974 on the Situation in Cyprus from the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe, 1983 (Box-folder 5: 13)
- Report of the Commission of the Council of Europe on Human Rights in Cyprus 1974, 1970s (Box-folder 5: 14)
- Report on Applications 9780/74 and 6950/75 Cyprus Against Turkey from the Council of Europe, 1976 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Parliamentary debate from the House of Lords Official Report, 1983 (Box-folder 6: 2)
- Cyprus Bulletin, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 6: 3)
- Report by the Secretary General of the United Nations Operation in Cyprus on the period 1 December 1986 - 29 May 1987 (Box-folder 6: 4)
- "Die Entwicklung Zyperns vom Britischen Pachtgebiet zur Unabhängigen Republik," and "Minderheitenschutz und Volkgruppenrecht Im 2o. Jarhundert Unter Besonderer Berücksichtigung der Verhältnisse Auf Zypern,", 1975-1980 (Box-folder 6: 5)
- Correspondence from M. Necati Münir Ertekün, 1986 (Box-folder 6: 6)
- Memoranda, notes, and articles regarding Cyprus, 1985 (Box-folder 6: 7)
- "Decision of the Commission as to the Admissibility of Application 8007/77 by Cyprus Against Turkey," from the Council of Europe, 1977 (Box-folder 6: 8)
- Turkish Cypriot proposals, 1989 (Box-folder 6: 9)
- Articles written by James Wolfe regarding Cyprus, 1979-1992 (Box-folder 6: 10)
- "The Cyprus Question: Some Facts," by Christos A. Theodoulou, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 11)
- Articles regarding Cyprus, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- Clippings, telex, memoranda, and press releases regarding and from the Embassy of Cyprus in Washington, D.C., 1978-1980 (Box-folder 7: 2)
- Press releases, newsletters, articles, and clippings regarding Cyprus, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 7: 3)
- Greek Cypriot proposals, 1989 (Box-folder 7: 4)
- Maps of Cyprus, 1964-1975 (Box-folder 7: 5)
- Materials regarding Cyprus from the United Nations, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 6)
- Printed matter, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 7: 7)
- Cyprus: Intercommunal talks, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 7: 8)
- Palley, Claire, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 7: 9)
- Kyprianou, H.E. Spyros, 1979-1999 (Box-folder 7: 10)
- Vassiliou, George, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 7: 11)
- Cyprus conspiracy theories, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 7: 12)
- International law, 1977-1991 (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Cyprus bar council, 1984 (Box-folder 8: 2)
- Soulioti, Stella, 1979-1998 (Box-folder 8: 3)
- Photocopy of Dis Politika, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 4)
- Acheson plans, 1965-1985 (Box-folder 8: 5)
- United States policy regarding Cyprus, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 8: 6)
- United States policy regarding Cyprus from the period 1978-1985 (Box-folder 8: 7)
- Cyprus, United States plan, 1979-1998 (Box-folder 8: 8)
- Cyprus, British documents, 1974-1990 (Box-folder 8: 9)
- Jacovides, A.J., 1979-1990 (Box-folder 8: 10-11)
- Willenz, Eric, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 8: 12)
- Platig, E. Raymond, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 8: 13)
- Clerides, Glafcos, 1998 (Box-folder 8: 14)
- Washington Institute for Near East Policy, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 8: 15)
- Cyprus bar council correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 9: 1)
- Cyprus interview schedule, 1979 (Box-folder 9: 2)
- Kyle, Keith, 1991 (Box-folder 9: 3)
- Department of state, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 9: 4)
- Cyprus contract, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 9: 5)
- Various materials regarding Cyprus, 1974-1990 (Box-folder 9: 6-7)
- "Intercommunal Negotiations on Cyprus: A Study of the Constitutional Dimension,", 1979 (Box-folder 9: 8)
- Nejatigil, Zaim, 1984 (Box-folder 9: 9)
- Material regarding a Cypriot agreement, undated (Box-folder 9: 10)
- Memorandum by the Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Cyprus, from the Government of the Republic of Cyprus, 1987 (Box-folder 9: 11)
- United Nations resolutions regarding Cyprus, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 10: 1)
- Articles regarding Cyprus, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 10: 2-4)
- Council of Europe materials regarding Cyprus, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 10: 5)
- United Nations Security Council framework, 1986 (Box-folder 10: 6)
- Turkish Cypriot proposals, 1978 (Box-folder 10: 7)
- Materials regarding the inter-communal negotiations, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 10: 8-10)
- Property rights documents, 1987 (Box-folder 10: 11)
- Cypriot proposals, 1978 (Box-folder 11: 1)
- American Universities Field Staff, 1981 (Box-folder 11: 2)
- Nicosia Master Plan, United Nations, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 11: 3)
- Conference with Matthew Nimetz, 1980 (Box-folder 11: 4)
- International law conference, clippings and notes, 1979 (Box-folder 11: 5)
- Cyprus and foreign policy nonalignment, 1988 (Box-folder 11: 6)
- Printed matter regarding Cyprus and international relations, undated (Box-folder 11: 7)
- Printed matter regarding Cyprus and international relations, 1964-1977 (Box-folder 11: 8-11)
- Printed matter regarding Cyprus and international relations, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
- Photocopy of Foreign Affairs Committee, Third Report Session 1986-1987 on Cyprus, to the House of Commons (Box-folder 13)